collincountytx.gov 2006-10-09

# Collin County Privacy Policy

Welcome

Thank you for visiting the Collin County website. This website is designed to make it easier and more efficient for Collin County citizens and businesses to interact with their local government.

Like all online resources, we recognize that visitors to this website are concerned about their privacy Collin County is committed to preserving your privacy when visiting this website.

This policy describes the Collin County's privacy practices regarding information collected from visitors to this website. This policy describes what data is collected and how that information is used.

Collin County may, at its sole discretion, change, modify, add, or delete portions of this policy. Because this privacy policy applies only to this website, you may wish to examine the privacy policy of any website, including other websites you access through this website.

We will collect no personal information about you when you visit our website unless you choose to provide that information to us. We do not give, share, sell, or transfer any personal information to a third party.

Information Collected When You Visit this Website

When visiting the Collin County website, the following information is collected and stored automatically about your visit:

  1. The type of browser used;
  2. The type of operating system used;
  3. The date and time you visited this site;
  4. The length of time you visited this site;
  5. The web pages or services you accessed at this site;
  6. The Referring URL;
  7. The search engine and search phrases used to find this site;
  8. The amount of data transferred;
  9. The IP address assigned to your ISP or your computer;
  10. The Location assigned to your IP address; and
  11. Name of the ISP assigned to your IP address.

The information gathered is used to improve this website's content and to help the County understand how people are using this website. This information is collected for statistical analysis, to determine what information is of most and of least interest to our visitors, and to identify system performance or problem areas (e.g. Those dealing with browser types and operating systems).

The information is not collected for commercial marketing purposes and Collin County does not sell or distribute the information collected from the Website for commercial or marketing purposes. We use the aggregated information from all of our visitors to measure server performance and improve the content of our site.

Disclosure of Information Collected Through This Website

Information collected through this website, personal or otherwise, may, if not protected by local, federal or state law, may be subject to disclosure pursuant to law, such as the [Freedom of Information Act (FOIA)](http://www.archives.gov/about_us/regulations/part_1250.html), or court order.

Collin County may disclose information to local, state or federal law enforcement authorities to enforce its rights against unauthorized access or attempted unauthorized access to the Collin County's information.

Security

For site security purposes and to ensure that this service remains available to all users, Collin County web servers employs industry standard hardware, software and methods to monitor network traffic to identify unauthorized attempts to upload or change information, or otherwise cause damage. 

We monitor network traffic to identify unauthorized attempts to upload or change information or to otherwise cause damage to the site. Anyone using this Web site expressly consents to such monitoring.

Unauthorized attempts to upload information or change information on Collin County servers are strictly prohibited and may be punishable by law, including the Computer Fraud and Abuse Act of 1986 and the National Information Infrastructure Protection Act.

Collin County limits employee access to personally identifiable information from this website to only those employees who need access to perform a specific job. Security measures have been integrated into the design, implementation, and day-to-day operations of this website as part of our continuing commitment to the security of electronic content as well as the electronic transmission of information.

In the specific context of this security monitoring, there is no expectation of privacy. However, only in the case of actual law enforcement investigations, will we attempt to identify individual users or their usage habits.

**NOTE:** The information contained in this policy should not be construed in any way as giving business, legal, or other advice, or warranting as fail proof the security of information provided via this website. For site security purposes and to ensure that this website remains available to all users, Collin County employs software to monitor traffic to identify unauthorized attempts to upload or change information or otherwise cause damage to this website.

Personal Information and Choice

"Personal information" is information about an individual (e.g. an individual's name, address, and phone number). A domain name or Internet Protocol address is not considered personal information.

Personal information is not collected through this website unless you send an email containing such information to the County through this website. If you do not communicate with this website it does not affect your ability to use any other features of this website or other government websites.

Collin County does not knowingly collect personal information from children or create profiles of children through this website. People are cautioned that the collection of personal information provided by any individual in an email will be treated the same as information given by an adult, and if not protected by federal or State law, be subject to public access. The County encourages parents and teachers to be involved in children's Internet activities and guide the children whenever children are asked to provide personal information on-line.

Information Collected When You Email this Website

If during your visit to this website you send an email to the County, your email address and the contents of your email will be collected. The information collected is not limited to text characters and may include attachments you send. 

Your email address, the information contained in your email and attachments may be used to respond to you, to address the issues you have identified, to further improve the website, or to forward your email to another agency for appropriate action. Your email address is not collected for commercial or marketing purposes and the Collin County does not sell or distribute your email address for commercial or marketing purposes.

Links Disclaimer

In order to provide visitors with certain information, this website provides links to local, state and federal government agencies, and websites of other organizations. A link does not constitute an endorsement of the content, viewpoint, accuracy, opinions, policies, products, services, or accessibility of that website. Once you link to another website from this website, you are subject to the terms and conditions of that website.

**Cautionary Note:** The Collin County privacy policy only applies to this web site. When you follow a link to another site, even to sites of state agencies, government entities, and Collin County officials, **this policy will not apply**. You should check the privacy policy of each of these sites if you have concerns about how they handle personally identifiable information.

Information Disclaimer

Information provided on this website is intended to allow the public immediate access to public information. While all attempts are made to provide accurate, current, and reliable information, the County recognizes the possibility of human and/or mechanical error.

Collin County, its employees, officers and agencies make no representations as to the accuracy, completeness or suitability of the information provided by this website, and deny any expressed or implied warranty as to the same.

The County reserves the right to make changes at any time and without notice, and assumes no liability for damages incurred directly or indirectly as a result of errors, omissions or discrepancies.

Collin County Logo

The Collin County logo is a protected trademark. Duplication and any use outside of official Collin County government business is prohibited.

Accessibility

Collin County is committed to ensuring accessibility of its website for people with disabilities. We plan for all new, updated, and existing web content produced by our organization to conform to [W3C/WAI's Web Content Accessibility Guidelines 2.0, Conformance Level 1](http://www.w3.org/TR/WCAG20/) by July 1, 2005. Third-party developers who provide new web content for our site will be asked to conform to [W3C/WAI's Web Content Accessibility Guidelines 2.0, Conformance Level 1](http://www.w3.org/TR/WCAG20/) as well. We will review this policy in the future to consider updating it to an advanced version of W3C's Web Content Accessibility Guidelines.

Contact Information

For questions regarding the Privacy & Accessibility Policy please contact: [webarchitect@collincountytx.gov](mailto:webarchitect@collincountytx.gov)
